Based on the incredible true story that inspired Moby Dick
In the Heart of the Sea is a thriller, drama,
adventure film directed by Ron Howard.
In the winter of 1820, the New England whaling ship Essex is assaulted by something no one could
believe—a whale of mammoth size and will, and an almost human sense of vengeance.
Owen Chase, played by Chris Hemsworth.
George Pollard, played by Benjamin Walker.
Matthew Joy, played by Cillian Murphy.
Old Thomas Nickerson, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Herman Melville, played by Ben Whishaw.
Mrs. Nickerson, played by Michelle Fairley.
In the Heart of the Sea is a 2015 historical adventure drama film directed and co-produced by Ron Howard
from a screenplay by Charles Leavitt and a story by Leavitt, Rick Jaffa, and Amanda Silver.
An international co-production between the United States and Spain, the film stars Chris
Hemsworth, Benjamin Walker, Cillian Murphy, Tom Holland, Ben Whishaw, and Brendan Gleeson.
It is based on Nathaniel Philbrick's 2000 non-fiction book In the Heart of the Sea: The Tragedy of the Whaleship Essex, about the
sinking of the American whaling ship Essex in 1820, an event that in part inspired Herman Melville's 1851 novel Moby-Dick.
The film premiered in New York City on December 7, 2015, and was released in
theaters in the United States on December 11, 2015, by Warner Bros.
In the Heart of the Sea received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office
failure, grossing only $94.3 million against a $100 million budget.
The film explores themes of sea, suicide, ship, ocean, whale.
The tone is emotional and intense.